A Guide to the Richard Harding Davis Collection 1879-1917, n.d.
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Richard Harding Davis Collection 1879-1917, n.d.
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6109-e
This collection consists of 114 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Contents List
- Poem beginning, "And is there no sweet spell..." n.d., AMs, 3 pp. (Box 14)
- Letters 1879-1917, n.d. (Box 14, 15)
  - Rutherford B. Hayes to Lemuel Clarke Davis June 5, 1879, ALS, 1 p. with envelope (Box 14)
  - Jefferson Davis to Col. A.K. McClure December 23, 1884, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
  - Oliver Wendell Holmes to George W[endell] Childs July 1, 1887, ALS, 2 pp. with envelope (Box 14)
  - Julia Marlowe to Richard Harding Davis April 10, 1891, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
  - Sir Henry Irving to Richard Harding Davis November 17, 1893, ANS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - George Curzon to Richard Harding Davis April 22, 1894, ALS, 4 pp. (Box 14)
  - Albert Chevalier to Richard Harding Davis March 21, 1895, ALS, 3 pp. (Box 14)
  - Ellen Terry to Richard Harding Davis December 25, 1895, ALS, 2 pp. with envelope (Box 14)
  - John Hay to Lemuel Clarke Davis November 26, 1896, ALS, 3 pp. with envelope (Box 14)
  - Sir Anthony Hope Hawkins to Richard Harding Davis January 25, 1897, ALS, 4 pp. (Box 14)
  - Theodore Roosevelt to Richard Harding Davis December 16, 1898, ALS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - Richmond Pearson Hobson to Richard Harding Davis July 6, 1899, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
  - Joseph Jefferson to Richard Harding Davis July 10, 1899, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
  - John Hay to Lemuel Clarke Davis August 11, 1900, ALS, 2 pp. with envelope (Box 14)
  - John Hay to Lemuel Clarke Davis November 30, 1900, TLS, 2 pp. with envelope (Box 14)
  - Winston Churchill to Richard Harding Davis December 17, 1900, ALS, 4 pp. (Box 14)
  - Corrie Reitz to Richard Harding Davis February 16, 1901, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
  - Arthur Pinero to Richard Harding Davis April 3, 1901, ALS, 3 pp. with envelope (Box 14)
  - Edward L[ivermore] Burlingame to Richard Harding Davis May 15, 1901, ALS, 3 pp. (Box 14)
  - Theodore Roosevelt to Richard Harding Davis December 28, 1901, ANS, 1 p. with envelope, autograph postscript (Box 14)
  - Anthony Hope Hawkins to Richard Harding Davis June 29, 1902, ALS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - Albert Chevalier to Richard Harding Davis October 7, 1902, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
  - [Francis William] Reitz to Richard Harding Davis November 8, 1902, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
  - Gordon A. Fraser to Richard Harding Davis November 14, 1902 (Box 14)
  - Owen Wister to Richard Harding Davis January 31, 1903, ALS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - Theodore Roosevelt to Richard Harding Davis February 11, 1903, TLS, 2 pp. with envelope (Box 14)
  - Augustus Thomas to Richard Harding Davis February 12, 1903, TLS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - Elihu Root to Richard Harding Davis March 17, 1903, TLS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - George Dewey to Richard Harding Davis July 28, 1903, TLS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - Theodore Roosevelt to Lemuel Clarke Davis September 21, 1903, TLS, 2 pp. with envelope (Box 14)
  - Winston Churcill to Richard Harding Davis September 26, 1903, TLS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - Theodore Roosevelt to Lemuel Clarke Davis October 5, 1903, TLS, 8 pp. with envelope (Box 14)
  - John Hay to Richard Harding Davis November 13, 1903, TLS, 1 p. (Box 13)
  - Theodore Roosevelt to Richard Harding Davis December 22, 1903, TLS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
  - [Elihu Root] to Richard Harding Davis December 26, 1903, TL (frag), 1 p. (Box 14)
  - Augustus Thomas to Richard Harding Davis January 2, 1904, TLS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - Owen Wister to Richard Harding Davis January 9, 1904, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
  - Francis Wilson to Richard Harding Davis August 6, 1904, ALS, 3 pp. (Box 14)
  - Jack London to Richard Harding Davis August 10, 1994, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
  - Jack London to Richard Harding Davis December 27, 1904, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
  - Theodore Roosevelt to Richard Harding Davis January 3, 1905, TLS, 3 pp. with envelope (Box 14)
  - Theodore Roosevelt to Richard Harding Davis [January 9, 1905], TNS, 1 p. with envelope (Box 14)
  - Theodore Roosevelt to Richard Harding Davis May 13, 1905, TLS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
    with autograph note
  - Robert W. Chambers to Richard Harding Davis October 26, 1905, ALS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - William Travers Jerome to Richard Harding Davis November 16, 1905, TLS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - Winston S. Churchill to Richard Harding Davis May 19, 1906, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
  - Jesse Lynch Williams to Richard Harding Davis May 31, 1906, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
  - Winston Churchill to Richard Harding Davis June 29, 1906, TLS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - Winston Churchill to Richard Harding Davis September 4, 1906, TLS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - Winston Churchill to Richard Harding Davis October 21, 1906, ALS, 3 pp. (Box 14)
  - Sir Gerald Du Maurier to Richard Harding Davis February 10, 1907, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
  - Sir Gerald Du Maurier to Richard Harding Davis March 8, 1907, ALS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - [Gouverneur Morris] to Charles [Belmont Davis] August 6, 1907, AL (frag.), 1 p. (Box 14)
  - Winston S. Churchill to Richard Harding Davis September 20, 1907, ALS, 3 pp. (Box 14)
    Churchill excuses Davis from any "malicious motive" for including material in Real Soldiers of Fortune(1906) that was inaccurate, "possibly-- libelous."
  - Dorothy Stanley to Richard Harding Davis February 14, 1908, ALS, 4 pp. (Box 14)
  - Anthony Hope Hopkins to Richard Harding Davis January 4, 1909, ALS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - Anthony Hope Hopkins to Richard Harding Davis January 22, 1909, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 15)
  - Anthony Hope Hawkins to Richard Harding Davis March 12, 1909, ALS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Anthony Hope Hawkins to Richard Harding Davis September 17, 1910, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 15)
  - Theodore Roosevelt to Richard Harding Davis October 1, 1910, December 24, 1910 (Box 15)
  - Gouverneur Morris to Richard Harding Davis December 28, 1910, ALS, 4 pp. (Box 15)
  - Anthony Hope Hawkins to Richard Harding Davis June 14, 1911, ALS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Anthony Hope Hawkins to Richard Harding Davis August 25, 1911, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 15)
  - Leonard Wood to Richard Harding Davis February 1, 1913, TLS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Augustus Thomas to Richard Harding Davis July 11, 1913, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 15)
  - Elihu Root to Richard Harding Davis December 18, 1913, TLS (Box 15)
  - George Dewey to Richard Harding Davis December 27, 1913, TLS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Stephen Whitman to Richard Harding Davis Feburary 6, 1914, ALS, 3 pp. (Box 15)
  - Theodore Roosevelt to Richard Harding Davis July 18, 1914, TLS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Winston Churchill to Richard Harding Davis October 31, 1914, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 15)
  - Jean Jules Jusserand to Richard Harding Davis November 4, 1914, TLS, 2 pp. (Box 15)
    With autographed calling card
  - Jean Jules Jusserand to Richard Harding Davis December 24, 1914, TLS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Theodore Roosevelt to Richard Harding Davis December 29, 1914, TLS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Anthony Hope Hawkins to Richard Harding to Davis January 3, 1915, ALS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - J. Brigenbleek to Richard Harding Davis January 15, 1915, ALS, 1 p. with envelope (Box 15)
  - Arthur ("Hugh") Frazier to Richard Harding Davis January 15, 1915, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 15)
  - [Finley] Peter [Dunne] to Richard Harding Davis Feburary 3, 1915, ALS, 4 pp. (Box 15)
  - Authors' League to Richard Harding Davis February 13, 1915, TLS, 1 p. (Box 15)
    Signed by Hamlin Garland, Rex Beach, Harvey O'Higgens, and Ellis P. Butler.
  - J. Brigenbleek to Richard Harding Davis March 11, 1915, ALS, 1 p. with envelope (Box 15)
  - Arthur Wing Pinero to Richard Harding Davis June 11, 1915, ALS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - George Barr McCutcheon to Richard Harding Davis April 3, 1916, ALS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Cyril Maude to Richard Harding Davis [April 3, 1916], ALS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Theodore Roosevelt to Charles Belmont Davis April 22, 1916, TLS, 1 p. with envelope (Box 15)
  - Augustus Thomas to Charles Belmont Davis June 5, 1916, TLS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Theodore Roosevelt to Charles Belmont Davis June 27, 1916, TLS, 1 p. with envelope (Box 15)
  - Herbert Bayard Swope to Elizabeth McEvoy Davis September 16, 1917, ALS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Rowland Thomas to [Richard Harding] Davis February 4, n.y., ALS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Charles Dana [Gibson] to [Richard Harding Davis] April 2, n.y., ALS, 3 pp. (Box 15)
  - Raymond Hitchcock to [Richard Harding] Davis June 11, n.y., ALS, 3 pp. (Box 15)
  - Paul Bourget to [Richard Harding] Davis June 15, n.y., ALS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Booth Tarkington to [Richard Harding] Davis June 24, n.y., ALS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - John Drew to [Richard Harding Davis] October 4, n.y., ALS, 2 pp. (Box 15)
  - Booth Tarkington to [Richard Harding] Davis October 7, n.y., ALS, 4 pp. (Box 15)
  - Paul Bourget to [Richard Harding Davis] n.d., ALS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Arthur Wing Pinero to [_______], introducing Richard Harding Davis n.d., ANS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Maude Adams to Richard Harding Davis n.d., ALS, 2 pp. (Box 15)
  - Anthony Hope Hawkins to Richard Harding Davis "Saturday", ALS, 3 pp. (Box 15)
  - [_________] to Richard Harding Davis "Thursday", ALS, 2 pp. (Box 15)
  - Edward H. Sothern to Richard Harding Davis n.d., ALS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Edward. H. Sothern to Richard Harding Davis n.d., ALS, 2 pp. (Box 15)
  - Irwin S[hrewsbury] Cobb to Richard Harding Davis "Tuesday", ALS, 2 pp. (Box 15)
  - [Francis William] Reitz to Richard Harding Davis n.d., ALS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Gouverneur Morris to Charles [Belmont Davis] n.d., ALS, 1p. (Box 15)
  - Gouverneur Morris to Richard Harding Davis n.d., ALS, 2 pp. (Box 15)
  - Gouverneur Morris to Richard Harding Davis "Friday", ALS, 2 pp. (Box 15)
  - Gouverneur Morris to Richard Harding Davis n.d., ALS, 3 pp. (Box 15)
  - Gouverneur Morris to Richard Harding Davis n.d., ALS, 3pp. (Box 15)
  - Gouverneur Morris to Richard Harding Davis n.d., ALS, 3 pp. (Box 15)
  - A[lfred]; E[dward]; W[oodley] Mason to Mrs. Richard Harding Davis n.d., ANS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Winston Churchill to Richard Harding Davis n.d., ALS, 4 pp. (Box 15)
  - Ellen Terry to Richard Harding Davis "Monday", ALS, 3 pp. (Box 15)
  - George Ade to Richard Harding Davis "Wednesday", ALS, 1 p. (Box 15)
    Ade is unable to see Davis due to heavy rehearsal schedule. ANS on card of "The Wolcott" states when he can be met.
  - Sir James M. Barrie to Richard Harding Davis July 11, n.y., ALS, 2 pp. (Box 15)